Dwight Ledet

Copenhagen, Denmark

Phone: +45 91 81 65 02 Email: dwightledet@protonmail.com

www.dwightledet.com | www.heraldjavelin.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Renewable energy automation software development and data analysis focusing on artificial intelligence and neural networks and their applications in the field of energy. Currently developing software for hybrid electricity / hydrogen production for offshore wind farms.

Drilling automation software development. Specialized automation for Constant Bottom Hole Pressure, Managed Pressure Drilling (MPD) and Closed Hole Circulation Drilling / Pressurized Mud Cap Drilling (CHCD / PMCD)

On-site Drilling Supervision and Project Management of Managed Pressure Drilling (MPD) / Closed Hole Circulation Drilling /Pressurized Mud Cap (CHCD / PMCD), directional / horizontal drilling, and related projects in the United States, Denmark (North Sea), Germany (North Sea), Japan, Kazakhstan (Caspian Sea), Thailand (Gulf of Thailand), Netherlands (North Sea) Qatar, Saudi Arabia, and the UAE.

EDUCATION

University of Stavanger – Masters Energy, Environment and Society | 2020 – Present Graduate Student

Renewable energy automation software development and data analysis focusing on artificial intelligence and artificial neural networks and their applications in the field of energy. Currently developing neural networks for hybrid electricity / hydrogen production for offshore wind farms. Active in the University of Stavanger Energy Group providing assistance in the geothermal development program.

Oregon State University – Science and Technology Studies

Bachelor of Arts (Dual Degree) Economics and History of Science

Rigorous examination of the history, nature and evolution of scientific ideas, practices, and institutions; their contemporary significance to intellectual life; and their material transformation of the modern world. Focused on science and technology, combining scientific and humanistic perspectives to understand how science develops and affects the world: how it relates to industry, policy, politics and the broader culture.

EXPERIENCE

Independent Professional Consultant | 2007 – 2019

Supervision of drilling automation software development to improve accuracy, reduce cost, increase uptime, and increase safety. Specialized automation for Constant Bottom Hole Pressure, Managed Pressure Drilling (MPD) and Closed Hole Circulation Drilling / Pressurized Mud Cap Drilling (CHCD / PMCD) on the following projects.

AGIP North Caspian Operating Co. N.V / ExxonMobil - Atyrau, Kazakhstan

Supervision of Managed Pressure/Pressurized Mud Cap (PMCD) drilling operations in a highly fractured carbonate reservoir, with severe and uncontrollable losses and high H₂S concentrations (above 25%), in the Kashagan East field located in the North Caspian Sea. On-site project supervision of PMCD drilling operations reporting all PMCD and related issues to management team in Kazakhstan. Prepared and instituted procedures and contingencies to overcome well control issues and maintain operations in a stable PMCD mode while drilling the critical portion of reservoir. Provide PMCD training and workshops for Operator, rig, and service personnel

Target Energy - Kenya, Africa

Supervision of directional drilling operations for Geothermal wells in the Menengai Crater - Nakuru, Kenya

Chevron - Perth / Barrow Island, Australia

Supervision of land based directional drilling project working with a team of office-based engineers and geologists on the design and execution of directional wells. Drilling program included horizontal directional production wells into the Mardie B formation as well as vertical and J-well designs for water source and CO2 injection for the Chevron Gorgon Project.

RasGas / ExxonMobil - Doha, Qatar

Project Management and on-site supervision of the Barzan Red-Well, Pressurized Mud Cap (PMCD) drilling operations in a high H₂S, fractured carbonate reservoir with severe and uncontrollable losses. Prepared rig and hole-specific operating procedures and contingency plans and provide PMCD training to office, engineering, drilling, and service personnel.

QatarGas / ConocoPhillips - Doha, Qatar

Provided on-site drilling supervision of an eight well, Pressurized Mud Cap (PMCD) drilling operation in a high H₂S, fractured carbonate reservoir with severe and uncontrollable losses. Prepared rig and well-specific operating procedures and contingency plans and provide PMCD training to office, engineering, drilling, and service personnel.

Royal Dutch Shell - Rijswijk, Netherlands

Drilling engineering supervisor for the Supervisory Control and Drilling Automation (SCADA) project. Provided office-based engineering support for the software automation team and on-site drilling supervision for SCADA deployment in the Groningen gas field.

Antero Resources - Pennsylvania, USA

Supervision of land-drilling operations for Coal Bed Methane (CBM) horizontal, underbalanced, concentric string, multilateral project

AGIP North Caspian Operating Co. N.V. - Kazakhstan

Supervision of multiple Managed Pressure/Pressurized Mud Cap Mud Cap (PMCD) drilling operations in a highly fractured carbonate reservoir with severe and uncontrollable losses and high H₂S concentrations (above 25%) in the Kashagan, Kairan, and Aktote fields located in the North Caspian Sea (Deutag T-47, Parker 257 (Sunkar), Pride 319, Saipem 401 & 402). On-site project supervision of PMCD drilling operations reporting all PMCD and related issues to management team in Kazakhstan. Instituted procedures and contingencies to overcome well control issues and maintain operations in a stable PMCD mode while drilling the critical portion of reservoir. Prepared operational procedures

and contingencies and conduct training and certification of rig crews, operator, and service personnel. Conduct HAZID/HAZOP.

Baker Hughes Inteq – International | 2003 – 2007

Drilling Systems Supervisor

On-site drilling systems supervisor in the following locations:

Perenco - Gabon, West Africa

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Grondin Field, Offshore Gabon

Royal Dutch Shell - Gabon, West Africa

On-site field supervision of horizontal-drilling projects in the Rabi Kounga Field, Western Gabon

Chevron - Songkhla, Thailand - Gulf of Thailand

On-site field supervision of horizontal-drilling projects in the Pattani Trough and the Malay Basin, Gulf of Thailand

PTT Exploration and Production - Phitsanoluk, Thailand

On-site field supervision of horizontal-drilling projects in the Sirikit Main Oilfield, Phitsanoluk Basin, Onshore Thailand

Gaz de France - Den Helder, Netherlands - North Sea

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Groningen gas field and the Dutch sector of the North Sea

Exxon Neftegas Limited - Sakhalin Island, Russia

On-site field supervision of extended reach horizontal drilling projects in the Chayvo Field, Sakhalin Shelf, Offshore Sakhalin Island, Russia

Saudi Aramco - Dammam, Saudi Arabia

On-site field supervision of performance vertical and multilateral extended reach horizontal drilling projects in the Ghawar Field, Eastern Saudi Arabia

Maersk Oil and Gas - Esbjerg, Denmark - North Sea

On-site field supervision of extended reach, multilateral, horizontal directional drilling projects in the Gorm Field, North Sea

Japan Petroleum Exploration Company - Tomakomai, Japan

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Yufutsu oil and gas field, eastern Tomakomai, Hokkaido

Abu Dhabi Company for Onshore Oil Operations (ADCO) - Abu Dhabi, UAE

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Bu Hasa oil field, West Abu Dhabi

Baker Hugues Inteq - USA | 2001 - 2003

Drilling Systems Supervisor

On-site drilling systems supervisor in the following locations:

Williston, North Dakota

On-site field supervision of multilateral, horizontal-drilling projects in the Bakken Formation, Williston Basin

Casper, Wyoming

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Jonah Field, Green River Basin

Grand Junction, Colorado

On-site field supervision of directional drilling projects in the Denver-Julesburg Basin, eastern Colorado and the Rulison Field, Piceance Basin, Northwestern Colorado

SOFTWARE PROGRAMING LANGUAGES

Python | SQL | PHP | JavaScript | R